Guide to the Douglas Fitchen papers, 1962-2008.
Fitchen, Douglas papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Douglas Fitchen papers, 1962-2008.
14-22-3691
Douglas. Fitchen
4 cubic feet.
Correspondence, printed material.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Subject files, reprints, course material, and correspondence relating to Fitchen's work in the Physics Dept.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor emeritus and former department chair in the Dept. of Physics, Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Subject files, reprints, course material, and correspondence relating to Fitchen's work in the Physics Dept.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Fitchen, Douglas.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University.Dept. of Physics.
Subjects:
Physics--Study and teaching--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Physics.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Chairmanship Files
Series II. Advisory Panels
Series III. Committees
Series IV. China-U.S. Physics Examination and Application Program
Series V. Publicity
Series VI. American Telephone and Telegraph Company (ATT)
Series VII. Atomic Energy Commission
Series VIII. Biophysics Department
Series IX. Laboratory of Atomic and Solid State Physics
Series X. Materials Science Center
Series XI. The National Insitutes of Health
Series XII. Oak Ridge National Laboratory
Series XIII. Physics Department
Series XIV. Proposals and Applications
Series XV. Correspondence
Series XVI. Course Materials
Series XVII. Reprints
Subseries XVIIa. Biochimica et Biophysica Acta
Subseries XVIIb. Chemical Physics Letters
Subseries XVIIc. Journal of Chemical Physics
Subseries XVIId. Molecular Crystals and Liquid Crystals
Subseries XVIIe. Physical Review B
Subseries XVIIf. Physical Review Letters
Subseries XVIIg. Solid State Communications
Subseries XVIIh. Synthetic Metals
Subseries XVIIi. Other Reprints and Presentations
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Chairmanship Files
  - Meeting with Provost and Chairs, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Physics Archives, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Physics Chairman Search, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Chairman Information, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Salary, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Physics Chair Items, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - University Hearing Board, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Series II. Advisory Panels
  - Advisory Panel, March-April 1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Advisory Panel, May-June 1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Advisory Panel, July-August 1985 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Advisory Panel, September-December 1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Advisory Panel, January-June 1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Advisory Panel, July-December 1986 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Advisory Panel, January-June 1987 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Series III. Committees
  - 2001 Committee (I), 2001 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 2001 Committee (II), 2001 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Committee on the University as an Employer (I), 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Committee on the University as an Employer (II), 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Materials Science Center Executive Committee, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Special Committee on Employees, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Series IV. China-U.S. Physics Examination and Application Program
  - China-U.S. Physics Examination and Application Program, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - China-U.S. Physics Examination and Application Program, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - China-U.S. Physics Examination and Application Program, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - China-U.S. Physics Examination and Application Program, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - China-U.S. Physics Examination and Application Program, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - China-U.S. Physics Examination and Application Program, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Series V. Publicity
  - Faculty Comments, Publicity(I), 1985 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Faculty Comments, Publicity (II), 1985 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Publicity for Research, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Publicity-Interviews, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Series VI. American Telephone and Telegraph Company (ATT)
  - ATT, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - ATT Computers, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Series VII. Atomic Energy Commission
  - Atomic Energy Commission, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Atomic Energy Commission Equipment, 1965-1968 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Atomic Energy Commission Final Report, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Atomic Energy Commission Memos, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Atomic Energy Commission Proposal, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Atomic Energy Commission Renewal (I), 1966 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Atomic Energy Commission Renewal (II), 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Atomic Energy Commission Renewal (III), 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Atomic Energy Commission Renewal (IV), 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Series VIII. Biophysics Department
  - Cornell Biophysics Program, 1973-1980 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Biophysics Committee, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Biophysics Advisory Committee, 1972-1977 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Biophysics Graduate Program Information (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Colloquia, 1963-1966 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Series IX. Laboratory of Atomic and Solid State Physics
  - Spectrograph, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - News, 1963-1973 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Staffing, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - General Information, 1970-1977 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Mailings, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Search, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Bement Committee, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Laboratory Space, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Series X. Materials Science Center
  - Materials Science Center, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Facility, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Proposals, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - A. Albrecht, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Series XI. The National Insitutes of Health
  - Proposal, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Renewal, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Series XII. Oak Ridge National Laboratory
  - RbF, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Li7F, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Series XIII. Physics Department
  - Physics Curriculum, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Physics Curriculum Revision, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Cornell Physical Sciences Building, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Government Relations, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Physics Major Review, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Breadth of Graduate Studies in Physics, 1993-1999 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Physics Major Photos, 1985-1994 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Graduate Student Photos, 1979-1999 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Series XIV. Proposals and Applications
  - Sloan Foundation Fellowship Application, 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Proposals, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Lilly Endowment Proposal, 1974-1977 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Optical Multichannel Analyzer Proposals, Etc., 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Contract Proposal, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Materials Science Center Proposal, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - NSF Proposal, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - NSF Proposal, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Series XV. Correspondence
  - American Physical Society Division of Solid State Physics, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Baumann, Dr. Gunther-Darmstadt, Germany, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Beyers, Bob-Stanford, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Buyers, W.J.L.-Atomic Energy of Canada, Ltd., 1968 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Cesium Halides, 1964-1966 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Christy, R.W.-Dartmouth College, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Cooper, Barbara H., 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - D'Aubigne, Dr. Y. Merle-Grenoble, France, 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Dolling, Dr. G-Oak Ridge National Laboratory, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Fowler, Dr. W. Beall-"The Physics of Color Centers", 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Fowler, Dr. W. Beall-"The Physics of Color Centers", 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Friauf, Robert J.-University of Kansas, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Handler, Paul-University of Illinois, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Ilmas, E.R.-Soviet Exchange Scientist, 1966-1968 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Kabler, Milton-U.S. Naval Research Laboratory, 1967-1969 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - King, Dr. R.D.-Atomic Energy Research Establishment, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Laser Correspondence-General Electric, 1963-1967 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Littauer, Raphael, 1975-1977 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Lynch, D.W.-Iowa State University, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Mullen, J.G.-Purdue University, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Mulliken, Robert S.-University of Chicago, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Pierce, Dr. C.B.-Sandia Corporation, 1966-1968 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Pressure Shift, LiF, 1966-1968 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Rabin, Dr. Herbert-U.S. Naval Research Laboratory, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Sabbatic Correspondence, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Senate Correspondence, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Wang, S.F.-University of Illinois, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Wilson, Ken, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - 1-Dimensional Conductors Talk, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1962-1966 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Series XVI. Course Materials
  - BioG 106, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Physics 101, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Physics 101 Study Guide, 2005-2006 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Physics 102, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Physics 102 Study Guide, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Physics 112, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Physics 112, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Physics 112 Laboratory Manual, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Physics 207, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Physics 207, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Physics 207, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Physics 207-208, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Physics 208, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Physics 208, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Physics 208, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Physics 208, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Physics 208, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Physics 208, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Physics 208, 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Physics 208, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Physics 208 Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Physics 213, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Physics 214, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Physics 223-227, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Physics 225, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Physics 225-226, 1963-1966 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Physics 226-228, 1962-1965 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Physics 227, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Physics 227 Problems and Notes, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Physics 227 Problem Sets and Exams, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Physics 228, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Physics 228 Exams, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Physics 237, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Physics 237 Problems and Solutions, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Physics 635 (I), 1984 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Physics 635 (II), 1984 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Physics 635 (III), 1984 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Physics 635, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Physics 635 Exams, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Slides (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Series XVII. Reprints
  - Subseries XVIIa. Biochimica et Biophysica Acta
    - Methamoglobin, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Resonance Spectra Chloroperoxidase, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Subseries XVIIb. Chemical Physics Letters
    - Alpha-Band Splitting, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - S2 Ion in NaI, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Subseries XVIIc. Journal of Chemical Physics
    - Cytochrome C, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Scattering from a Helical Biopolymer, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - S2-Ion, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Cis (CH)x, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Subseries XVIId. Molecular Crystals and Liquid Crystals
    - Raman Probes, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Raman Results in (CH)x, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Subseries XVIIe. Physical Review B
    - Field and Temperature on Radiative Lifetime of F-Center, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - F in CsF, Properties, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Stark Effects in F-Transmission, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - CsCl, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Absorbed Oxygen, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Picosecond Dynamics, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - FB and Shift, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - F-Center in CsF, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - NO2, Raman and Vibronic Spectra, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Frank-Condon Approach, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Subseries XVIIf. Physical Review Letters
    - F3 in NaF, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Zero-Phonon Lines, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Stark Effects on F, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - MCP in F-Emission, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Subseries XVIIg. Solid State Communications
    - M'and R' Centers, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - J-T of R' in LiF, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Dichroism R' in LiF, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - T of F-Center Luminescence in KCl, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - MCD of F3+, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Alkali Fluoride Raman, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Raman Scattering in (SN)x Crystals, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Raman Scattering in TTF Crystals, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Raman Scattering in Mono. RbCoF3, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - (CH)x with Bromine and Iodine, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - (CD)x, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Infrared Luminescence in (CH)x, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Subseries XVIIh. Synthetic Metals
    - (CH)x and Analog, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - 1Ag State, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Subseries XVIIi. Other Reprints and Presentations
    - Sawicki and Fitchen Article, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - American Chemical Society-Resonance of Heme Proteins, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences-Brominated (SN)x, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Applied Physics Letters-Electroluminescent Diodes, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Biochemistry-CPO, Horseradish, Peroxidase and Cytochrome C, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Biopolymers-Racemic Poly-Benzyl-Glutamate, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Budapest Conference-Zero-Phonon Luminescence, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Chemica Scripta-(CH)x and (CD)x, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Engineering Outlook, University of Illinois, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - International Conference on Raman Spectroscopy, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - International Conference on the Science and Technology of Synthetic Metals-Picosecond Relaxation, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Journal of Physical and Chemical Solids-AgZn, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - Light Scattering-F9 Raman, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - Magnons and Magnetic Excitations-Raman Scattering in Co Perovskites, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - Physical Status Solidi-Linear Stark Effect in R', 1971 (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - Physics Letters-Impurity-Induced Raman Spectra, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - Physics of Color Centers-Zero Phonon Transitions, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - Picosecond Dynamics-Notes, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - Picosecond Relaxation, Trans Polyacetylene-Notes, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - Raman Scattering in Crystals on TTF-TCNQ, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - Review of Scientific Instruments-Pressure Cell, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - Reviews of Modern Physics-Optical Analogs, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - Tallinn-Raman Scattering by Impurities, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - Isomerization and Spin Generation in Polyacetylene, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 84)